A philosopher once asked,
一位哲人曾經問過
"Are we human because we gaze at the stars,
"是因為我們仰望繁星從而成為人類"
"or do we gaze at them because we are human?"
"還是因為我們是人類所以才仰望星空呢？"
Pointless, really.
這樣問其實沒有意義
Do the stars gaze back?
星星也注視著我們嗎？
Now, that's a question.
這才算有意義的問題
But I'm getting ahead of myself.
但是我好像說得早了點
Our story really begins here,
我們的故事真正從這裡開始
150 years ago at the Royal Academy of Science
150年前  位於England的 London市的Royal Academy科學院...
where a letter arrived, containing a very strange inquiry.
...收到了一封信 信中提到一個非常奇怪的問題
It had come from a country boy
寄信人是一個鄉村男孩
and the scientist who read it thought it might be a practical joke of some kind.
讀了信的科學家認為這可能 是個小小的惡作劇
But he duly wrote a reply
但是他還是正式的寫了回信
politely explaining that the query was nonsense.
禮貌的解釋道那個懷疑只能算是胡亂的猜測
And posted it to the boy who lived in a village called Wall,
信寄回了男孩的故鄉  一個叫Wall的小鎮
so named, the boy had said, for the wall that ran alongside it.
按照男孩的說法 名字來源於圍繞在小鎮外的牆
A wall that, according to local folklore, hid an extraordinary secret.
根據當地的民間傳說 那堵牆隱藏著一個不尋常的秘密
I'm charged with guarding the portal to another world.
我的責任就是  守衛這個通向另一個世界的入口
And you're asking me to just let you through?
而你居然想要我放你過去？
Yes. Because, let's be honest, it's a field.
Yes  因為  老實說  那邊只是片荒野
Look, do you see another world out there?
你瞧  你看見那邊有另一個世界麼？
No. You see a field. Do you see anything nonhuman?
No  你只能看到荒野 你看到任何非人間的東西嗎？
No. And you know why? Because it's a field!
No  你知道為什麼嗎？因為它只是一片荒野！
Hundreds of years, this wall's been here.
幾百年來  這堵牆就一直矗立在此
this gap's been under 24-hour guard.
幾百年來  這個缺口就24小時有人看守
- Well... - One more word,
- Well... - 你再多說一句
and I'll have you up in front of the village council!
我就把你送到村委會去！
- Well, that sounds rather final. - Yeah.
- Well  聽起來沒得商量了 - Yeah
- Better just go home, then, I suppose. - Right, then. Night, Dunstan.
- 我想我最好還是回家去 - 沒錯  晚安  Dunstan
Give my best to your father.
替我向你父親問好
Stop!
站住！
I don't deal with time-wasters.
我不和浪費時間的人做生意
Get over here and tend this stall.
滾過來打理這個攤子
I'm off to The Slaughtered Prince for a pint.
我要去Slaughtered酒吧喝上一杯
See anything you like?
看到喜歡的東西了麼？
Definitely.
確實
I mean, what I meant was these ones, the blue ones.
我是說...我是指這些  藍色的這些花
How much are they?
多少錢？
They might be the color of your hair.
它們可以用你頭髮的顏色來交換
Or they might be all of your memories before you were three.
或者用你三歲以前的全部記憶來換
I can check if you like.
你喜歡的話我現在就可以結帳
Anyway, you shouldn't buy the bluebells. Buy this one instead.
不管怎樣  你不應該買那個野風信子 買這個來代替吧
Snowdrop.
雪蓮花
It'll bring you luck.
它會給你帶來好運
But what does that cost?
不過我得為這個付出什麼呢？
This one costs a kiss.
這個要付出一個吻
Is she gone?
她走了嗎？
Follow me.
跟我來
I'm a princess, tricked into being a witch's slave.
我是個公主  被詭計陷害成了女巫的奴隸
Will you liberate me?
你能解救我嗎？
It's an enchanted chain. I'll only be free when she dies.
這是一根魔法鎖鏈 只有她死了我才能獲得自由
Sorry.
不好意思
Well, if I can't liberate you, what do you want of me?
Well  既然我無法解救你 我應該付給你什麼呢？
So, the scientist was wrong.
所以  那位科學家錯了
The wall had successfully done its job
這堵牆成功地完成了它的使命
of hiding the magical kingdom of Stormhold.
保護著魔法王國Stormhold城 使其不被發現
The young man returned that night to his home in England,
年輕人當晚就回到了他在England的家裡
hoping that his adventure would soon be forgotten.
祈盼著他這次的冒險會逐漸被人們所遺忘
But nine months later, he received an unexpected souvenir.
但9個月之後 他收到了一個意想不到的"紀念品"
This was left at the wall for you. It says here his name is Tristan.
在牆邊發現了這個  是給你的 裡面寫著小孩的名字叫Tristan
Tristan? Don't forget the flowers.
Tristan？別忘記帶上花
Yes. I've got them. Thank you, Father.
Yes  我已經帶上了  謝謝你  父親
Eighteen years passed, and the baby Tristan grew up
18年過去  當年的嬰兒Tristan已經長大成人
knowing nothing of his unconventional heritage.
對自己非比尋常的身世一無所知
But never mind how the infant became a boy.
不過怎樣從一個嬰兒長大成為一個青年 這無關重要
This is the story of how Tristan Thorn becomes a man,
這個故事是關於Tristan Thorn 如何成為一個男人的
a much greater challenge altogether.
總而言之  這得經歷非常大的挑戰
For to achieve it,
為了實現目標
he must win the heart of his one true love.
他必須贏得他所鍾愛的人的芳心
- It's him!
- 是他！
Humphrey?
Humphrey？
- No, it's Tristan. - Oh.
- No  我是Tristan - Oh
Did I leave something at the shop?
我有什麼東西落在商店裡嗎？
No. I just thought I could bring...
No  我只是想  我可以把這個...
Tristan Thorn,
Tristan Thorn
shop boy by day, peeping Tom by night.
白天在商店裡跑腿  晚上就出來偷看女人
Is there no end to your charms?
你就沒有別的追求了嗎？
Humphrey, there's no need to be like that.
Humphrey  沒必要那樣
Be nice to the poor boy.
對這個可憐的小子好一點
Were those for Victoria?
那些是想送給Victoria的嗎？
You were always useless at fencing in school, Tristan.
在學校裡  你的劍術總是那麼差勁  Tristan
In fact, I'm having trouble remembering if there was anything you were good at.
實際上  我真的是難以想像你到底擅長什麼
Humphrey, that's enough.
Humphrey  夠了
Are you all right?
你還好嗎？
Yeah. Yeah, fine.
Yeah  Yeah  還好
- Want some breakfast? - No, I'm really late for work.
- 來點早餐？ - 不了  我快遲到了
- Are you all right? - Yeah. Fine. Why?
- 你還好吧？ - Yeah  還好  怎麼了？
Oh, I don't know. Last night, how'd it go?
Oh  我也不知道  昨晚發展得怎麼樣？
Oh, really good. Really, really good.
Oh  很不錯  真的  很不錯
Hello, Tristan.
Hello   Tristan
- Victoria. - Pound of sugar, please.
- Victoria - 請給我一磅糖
- Yes. - Let's see, a bag of flour, a dozen eggs.
- Yes - 讓我看看...還要一袋麵粉...再來一打雞蛋
Oh, look, I'm sorry about last night. Humphrey was really rude.
Oh  對了  昨晚的事我很抱歉 Humphrey太粗魯了
I also need a sack of potatoes and some chocolate, please.
我還要一大袋土豆和幾塊巧克力  謝謝
May I perhaps see you tonight?
我今晚可以去見你麼？
No, but you may walk me home.
No  但你可以送我回家
Now?
現在嗎？
Yes. Yes, I can.
Yes. Yes  沒問題
Father, I lost my job.
父親  我的飯碗沒了
Father, I don't... I lost my job. I'm sorry.
父親  我沒能...我把工作丟了  對不起
- Father... - You lost your job.
- 父親... - 你把工作丟了
Yes, so I heard.
Yes  我都聽見了
Father, I'm sorry. I...
父親  非常抱歉...我...
Maybe Mr. Monday was right. Maybe I am deluding myself.
或許Monday先生說得對  或許我真是在自欺欺人
- I'm not good enough for Victoria. - He said that? That's poppycock.
- 我配不上Victoria - 他是那樣說嗎？簡直是一派胡言
You really want to know how it went last night?
你真想知道昨晚怎樣發展嗎？
Yeah.
Yeah
Not good.
沒指望
Come on. I'm wasting my time.
算了吧  我是在浪費時間
I'm not like Humphrey.
我不像Humphrey
Tristan, I can tell you that every man I ever envied when I was a boy
Tristan  我可以告訴你 每一個我小的時候嫉妒過的人
has led an unremarkable life.
他們現在的生活都是再普通不過了
So you don't fit with the popular crowd. Now, I take that as a very good omen.
所以你和那些普通人格格不入 我倒認為是一個很好的兆頭
- Tristan, I clearly said... - I know. You told me not to come.
- Tristan  我已經說得很清楚了... - 我知道  你叫我別再來
I have something for you. A surprise.
我有東西要給你  一個驚喜
No...
No...
It's not my birthday for another week, you know.
你是知道的  我的生日還有一周才到呢
- I've never had champagne before. - Yeah, me, neither.
- 我以前從沒喝過香檳 - 是啊  我也沒有
My God! This is delicious!
天哪！美味極了
How did... Well, how does a shop boy afford all of this?
你是怎麼...Well 一個在商店打雜的男孩是怎麼搞到這個？
I'm not a shop boy.
我不是在商店打雜的
God! I heard. I'm sorry. What are you going to do now?
老天！我聽說了  對不起  你現在打算做什麼呢？
No. I mean, I'm not a shop boy. I was just working in a shop.
No  我的意思是我不是在商店打雜的 我只是在商店裡幹活而已
And now I'm not. Now I'm free to live my life as I wish.
而現在我不幹了  現在我自由了 可以過我喜歡的生活
This must have been all your savings.
這東西一定花掉了你全部的積蓄
So? I can make more. That's the beauty of it.
又如何？我可以賺更多  多麼美好的未來
I never intended to stay in Wall, Victoria.
我從沒打算在圍牆裡過一輩子  Victoria
There's a big world out there, I'm gonna make my fortune.
外面的世界是多麼廣闊  我要去創造我的財富
Now you sound just like Humphrey. He's quite a traveler.
你現在的口氣就像Humphrey 他徹頭徹尾是一個旅行者
Do you know he's going all the way to lpswich just to buy me a ring?
你知道嗎？他將一路走去Ipswich 只是為了給我買枚戒指
Lpswich?
Ipswich？
Victoria, I'm talking about London or Paris or...
Victoria  我說的是London  Paris  還有...
A ring? Why is he... What kind of a ring?
戒指？為什麼他...什麼樣的戒指？
The word is he's planning to propose to me on my birthday.
他打算在我生日那天向我求婚
He's going to...
他準備...
And you're gonna say yes.
你會答應他嗎？
I can't exactly say no after he's gone all the way to lpswich.
我怎能拒絕他...他一路走去Ipswich喔！
"All the way to lpswich"?
"一路走去Ipswich"？
Victoria, for your hand in marriage, I'd cross oceans or continents.
Victoria  為了執子之手與子偕老 我願意攀山涉水...不惜一切
- Really? - Yes.
- 真的嗎？ - Yes
Victoria, for your hand in marriage,
Victoria  為了執子之手與子偕老
I would go to the gold fields of San Francisco
我願意到San Francisco的金礦淘金
and bring you back your weight in gold.
給你帶回和你一樣重的金子
I would.
我會的
I'd go to Africa and bring you back a diamond as big as your fist.
我願意去Africa洲 給你帶回和你拳頭般大小的鑽石
Or I'd go to the Arctic and I'd slaughter a polar bear
或者我會去Arctic手刃一隻北極熊
and bring you back its head.
然後把它的頭帶回給你
A polar bear's head?
一隻北極熊的頭？
You're funny, Tristan.
你太有趣了  Tristan
People like you and people like me, we're just not...
像你這樣的人和像我這樣的人  我們不僅是...
I should be going. It's really late.
我得走了. 已經很晚了
Well, hold on, then. Let's at least finish the champagne.
Well  等等  至少讓我們把香檳喝完
Okay.
Okay
Had Tristan known then how the stars watched Earth,
如果Tristan知道當時群星是怎樣注視著地球
he'd have shuddered at the very thought
他一定很擔心會被這些特別的觀眾羞辱
But, fortunately for him,
不過  他很幸運
nearly every star in the sky was at that moment
幾乎天空中所有的星星  在那一刻
looking in earnest at the land on the other side of the wall,
都很認真的注視著牆的另一邊的世界
where the King of all Stormhold lay on his deathbed,
Stormhold城的國王正躺在臨終的床上
which was a coincidence because it was the King's final act
也許只是個巧合  因為國王臨死的最後行為...
that would change the course of Tristan's destiny forever.
...將會永遠的改變Tristan一生的命運
Where is Secundus?
Secundus在哪？
He's on his way, Father.
他正趕回來  父親
Then we shall wait.
那我們等等吧
Sorry I'm late, Father. I came as swiftly as I was able.
抱歉  我遲到了  父親 我已經是以最快的速度趕回來的
Septimus.
Septimus
Primus.
Primus
Tertius.
Tertius
So, to the matter of succession.
那麼  關於繼承權的問題
Of my seven sons, there are four of you today still standing.
我的7個孩子中  今天仍有4個站在這裡
This is quite a break with tradition. I had 12 brothers.
這完全可以說是破先例了  我有12個兄弟
And you killed them all for your throne
而您為了奪得王位  甚至在您父親...當時的國王... 還沒感到不適之前就把他們全都殺死了
We know, Father. You're strong and courageous.
我們都知道  父親  你很強壯  也很勇敢
And cunning. Most importantly, cunning.
還有奸詐  這是最重要的  奸詐
- Secundus. - Yes, Father?
- Secundus - Yes  父親
Look through the window. Tell me what you see.
看出窗外  告訴我你看見了什麼
I see the kingdom, Father.
我看見了王國  父親
The whole of Stormhold.
整個Stormhold城
- And? - My kingdom?
- 還有呢？ - 我的王國？
Maybe. Look up.
可能是  朝上看
- Secundus. - Sextus. Quartus. Quintus.
- Secundus - Sextus  Quartus  Quintus
You're alive. You're...
你們還活著  你們...
Stuck like this till the new king is crowned.
像這樣被困著  直到新國王加冕
I was that close.
我離國王寶座是那麼近
Well, at least you haven't lost your looks.
Well  至少你看起來還像個人樣
Oh, please. You're not annoyed about that whole murder thing, are you?
Oh  拜託  你不是還在耿耿於懷被謀殺的事吧？
- I mean, that was 10 years ago. - Yeah.
- 我的意思是  那已經是10年前的事了 - Yeah
Great deal of good it did you, didn't it, killing me, Secundus?
你幹的非常利索  不是嗎  殺死了我  Secundus？
Because now, of course, now you are King of all Stormhold.
因為現在理所當然的 你就是Stormhold城的國王了
Oh, sorry. Wait. No, you're not. You're dead.
Oh  不好意思  等等...No 你不是已經...？你已經死了
Una? Una?
Una？Una？
No, Father, it's me, your son.
No  父親  是我  您的兒子
Tertius.
Tertius
Where is your sister, Una?
你的姐姐Una在哪？
Sorry, Father. Nobody has seen Una for years now.
抱歉  父親  已經好幾年沒有人見到過Una了
- Septimus? - What?
- Septimus - 什麼事？
Tradition dictates the throne must pass to a male heir.
傳統規定王位必須傳給男性繼承人
Exactly, Father.
沒錯  父親
So why would I kill my sister when these cretins are still alive?
那麼  這幾個白癡都還活著 我為什麼要殺我的姐姐？
Indeed.
確實是這樣
Therefore, we shall resolve the situation in a non-traditional manner.
因此我們要以非傳統的方式來解決現在這個局面
Only he of royal blood can restore the ruby.
只有擁有皇室血統的人才能重鑄這塊紅寶石
And the one of you that does so shall be the new King of Stormhold.
無論你們中哪一個成功辦到 他就是Stormhold城的新國王了
Oh, Tristan! A shooting star!
Oh  Tristan！一顆流星！
Beautiful.
太美了
More beautiful than a fancy ring from lpswich?
要比來自lpswitch的昂貴戒指更美  是嗎？
Victoria, for your hand in marriage,
Victoria  為了執子之手與子偕老
I'd cross the wall and I'd bring you back that fallen star.
我願意越過牆去把那顆墜落的星星帶回給你
You can't cross the wall.
你不能越過牆去
Nobody crosses the wall. Now you're just being silly.
沒人被允許越過牆  你剛才是發傻了吧
I'm not being silly. I'd do it.
我沒有發傻  我願意那麼做
For you, I'd do anything.
為了你  我願意做任何事
My very own star.
我自己的星星
It seems we have ourselves an agreement.
看起來我們達成約定了
You have exactly one week or I'm marrying Humphrey.
你只有一星期的時間 否則我就會嫁給Humphrey
Mormo! Empusa! Wake up. Now!
Mormo！Empusa！快醒醒  快點！
- What is it? - A star has fallen.
- 怎麼了？ - 有一顆星星墜落了
Where are the Babylon candles?
巴比倫蠟燭在哪？
You used the last one, Lamia, 200 years ago. Do you not recall?
兩百年前你就用完最後一根了 Lamia  你不記得了？
Perhaps we can obtain another.
也許我們能再弄到一根
Has your mind become as decrepit as your face, Empusa?
難道你的腦子就像你的臉一樣腐爛了嗎  Empusa？
You speak as if such things are freely available.
你說得好像它們能白白得到似的
I know, sister, I merely thought...
我知道  姐姐  我只是想...
You'd have us hunting for a Babylon candle
你想讓我們去找一根巴比倫蠟燭... 當其他女巫都去追尋我們的星星之時？
Fool. There's no time to waste.
豬頭  已經沒時間可浪費了
If we must retrieve it on foot, then we shall.
即使我們要徒步去找  我們也得去
Mormo, we need information.
Mormo  我們要知道方位
If these divinations are correct, the fallen star lies 100 miles away.
如果這些兆示是正確的話 那顆墜落的星星就在100英里外
Four centuries we've waited for this. What hardship a few more days?
我們為此已經等了4個世紀 再多辛苦幾天又何妨？
Which of us shall go, then, to seek it and bring it back?
我們中誰去把它找回來呢？
- I've his kidney. - I've his liver.
- 我拿到腎 - 我拿到肝臟
And I've his heart.
而我拿到心臟
You'll be needing what's left of the last star.
你需要上一顆星星留下的東西
- There's not much left. - Soon, there'll be plenty for us all.
- 沒剩多少了 - 很快  我們又會有很多的了
- Dunstan Thorn. Not again. - It's Tristan, actually.
- Dunstan Thorn  休想再來一次 - 實際上我是Tristan
Oh. You do look a bit like your father.
Oh  你看起來可真像你父親
And I suppose you intend to cross the wall as well, do you?
而且我想你也一樣是打算要越過這堵牆  是麼？
Well, you can forget it. Go home.
Well  你想都別想  快回家去吧
Cross the wall as well as who?
像誰一樣越過這道牆？
No one. Nobody.
沒誰  沒有人
Nobody crosses the wall. You know that!
沒有人曾越過這道牆  你知道的
Everybody knows that!
每個人都知道！
Yeah... No, no, I know. I understand. Nobody.
Yeah... No no  我明白  我瞭解  沒有人
Well, I better just head for the old homestead, then.
Well  那我最好還是回家吧
Yeah.
Yeah
- Right, then. Night, Tristan. - Good night.
- 對了  就這樣  晚安  Tristan - 晚安
Give my best to your father.
替我向你父親問好
Off you go.
你還是回去吧
I thought I heard you come in. Hey, what happened? Are you hurt?
我想我聽見你進門的聲音了
No, I'm fine.
No  我沒事
- That Humphrey again? - No.
- 又是Humphrey幹的？ - No
Actually, it was the guard. The guard at the wall.
事實上  是那個看守  那個看守牆的人
Tristan, he's 97 years old.
Tristan  他已經97歲了
Well, that's given him plenty of time to practice, then, hasn't it?
Well  所以他有足夠的時間來練習  不是嗎？
Why, may I ask, were you trying to cross the wall?
我能問問為什麼你要越過那堵牆嗎？
I might ask you the same thing.
我正想要問你同樣的問題
I have a mother.
我有個母親
I mean, I have a mother. She could still be alive.
我是指  親生母親  她可能還活著
Oh, I hope so. I certainly like to think so.
Oh  我也希望如此  我當然是這樣想
The chain you cut.
是你切斷的鏈條
Just like you said.
如你說的一樣
And...
還有...
And the glass flower. The flower she sold to you.
還有那朵花  她賣給你的那朵花
She told me it would bring me luck.
她跟我說這會帶給我好運
Thank you.
謝謝
This was also in the basket. I've never opened it.
這個也在那個籃子裡  我從沒有打開過
It's addressed to you.
是寫給你的
Yep.
Yep
"My dearest Tristan, please know that I only ever wanted the best for you."
"親愛的Tristan  你要明白 我只想把最好的留給你"
Had my mistress allowed it, I would have kept you in a heartbeat.
"若我的主人允許  我會與你形影不離的"
My dearest wish is that we will meet someday.
"我最大的願望就是有一天能與你相聚"
The fastest way to travel is by candlelight.
"最快的旅行方式就是利用蠟燭的光"
To use it, think of me and only me.
"使用它時想著我  就想著我一個人"
I will think of you every day, for always.
"我會每天都念著你  直到永遠"
"Your mother."
"你的母親"
Well, do you... Do you have a light?
Well  你有...你有火嗎？
Mother?
媽媽？
Oh! Oh, Mother, I'm so... I'm so sorry. Are you all right?
Oh! Oh  媽媽  我很...我很抱歉  你沒事吧？
No, I'm not. And I'm not your mother, so get off me!
不  我有事  並且我也不是你的母親 所以從我身上滾下去
You're... You're not my mother?
你不...你不是我母親？
Do I look like I'm your mother?
我看起來像是你的母親嗎？
No.
No
Sorry.
很抱歉
Well, are you all right? Do you want some help?
Well  你沒事吧？需要幫忙嗎？
You can help by leaving me alone!
離我遠點就當是幫我忙了
All right.
那好吧
Oh, my God. "Light the candle and think of me."
哦  天啊  "點燃蠟燭並且想著我"
I was. I was thinking of my...
原先我是想著我的...
But then Victoria and the star just popped into...
但接著Victoria和那顆星忽然閃過腦子...
Oh, excuse me, madam. Sorry.
Oh  打擾一下  女士  不好意思
This may seem strange, but have you seen a fallen star anywhere?
這樣問可能有點奇怪 但你有沒有看到一顆星掉下來了？
- You're funny. - No, really, we're in a crater.
- 你真搞笑 - No  說真的  我們就在一個隕石坑裡面
This must be where it fell.
這一定是它掉下來的地方
Yeah, this is where it fell.
Yeah  這就是它掉下來的地方
It is. Or if you want to be really specific,
沒錯  如果你想知道得更具體些
up there is where this weird, bloody necklace
她本來在上面的  這條該死的怪異項鍊...
came out of nowhere and knocked it out of the heavens
不知道從哪裡飛來  在她正想著自己的事情之時 把她從天空中砸了下來
And over there is where it landed.
而那邊就是她掉下來的地方
And right here, this is where it got hit by a magical flying moron!
而這裡  就在這裡我被一個會飛的神奇白癡撞到了
You're the star! You're the star? Really?
你就是那顆星！你就是那顆星？真的？
Oh, wow. I'm sorry. I had no idea you'd be a...
Oh  wow  對不起  我不知道你就是那顆...
May I just say in advance that I am sorry?
首先請允許我說聲對不起
- Sorry for what? - For this.
- 為什麼道歉？ - 為了這個
Now, if I am not mistaken, this means you have to come with me.
現在  如果我沒搞錯的話 這意味著你必須得跟我走了
See, you're going to be a birthday gift for Victoria, my true love.
看樣子 你要被當作生日禮物送給我的最愛Victoria了
But of course!
是啊！
Nothing says romance like the gift of a kidnapped, injured woman!
綁架一個受傷的女人做生日禮物 沒什麼比這更浪漫了！
I'm not going anywhere with you.
我哪裡都不會跟你去的
Hurry. You should be on your way now, Primus.
快點  你應該開始行動了  Primus
You must find the royal necklace with the ruby before your brothers.
你得在你兄弟之前找到那條紅寶石皇家項鍊
I should like to see you take the throne. The first benevolent king.
我真的希望看到你得到王位 成為首個仁慈的君主
I don't doubt Stormhold would be a better place under your rule.
我毫不懷疑  在你的統治下 Stormhold城會變得更加美好
Really?
真的？
Well, that is fascinating.
Well  那可真是太好了
- Don't you think, Tertius? - Yes, indeed.
- 你不這樣想嗎  Tertius？ - Yes  確實
Prince Septimus! Tertius. Well... Well. Well, well, I...
Septimus王子！Tertius  Well... Well  Well  well...我
Since you're all here, won't you join me in a toast?
既然你們都在這  何不一起來一杯呢？
What a very good idea.
真是個不錯的主意
To the new King of Stormhold,
敬Stormhold城的新國王
whichever of you fine fellows it might be.
不管你們兄弟中誰成為國王
You!
你！
You really thought that you were king?
你真認為自己會成為國王？
- You killed the Bishop? - No, Primus.
- 你殺死了主教？ - No  Primus
I think you'll find that you killed the Bishop by drinking out of the wrong cup.
我想你應該能意識到其實是你害死主教的 因為你拿錯了杯子
Oh, look, when you finish wrestling with your conscience,
Oh  聽著  當你還在受良心折磨時
may I suggest you return to your chamber?
我可以建議你還是回到你的房間麼？
Leave the quest for the stone to me.
找石頭的事就交給我吧
How have we lived this way all these years?
這些年來我們怎麼能一直住在這麼破的地方？
In my absence, I expect you to make it fit for the queens we are.
我不在時  希望你們能把它收拾得 適合像我們這樣的女王居住
When I return with our prize, all of us shall be young again.
當我滿載而歸的時候  我們都會再次年輕了
Never fear, my sisters.
不要害怕  我的姐妹們
I will not fail.
我不會失敗的
Don't you ever sleep?
你從不睡覺的嗎？
Not at night.
不在晚上睡
May have escaped your notice, genius,
你可能沒有注意到  天才
but that's when stars have rather better things to do.
不過現在是星星們要做更加重要的事情的時候
They're coming out, shining, that sort of thing.
她們會出現  閃耀  等等
Yeah, well, it may have escaped yours, but you're not in the sky anymore.
Yeah   well  不過你也可能沒有注意到 你已經不在天上了
Coming out is off the agenda.
離開天空就不需要遵守規矩
Shining has been suspended until further notice.
發光嘛  只能暫停等待另行通知
Oh, and sleeping during the day is O-U-T.
Oh  還有  在白天睡覺的日子...沒...有...啦
Unless you have some magical ability to sleep while you're walking.
除非你有什麼可以邊走邊睡的魔法
Have you not got it into your thick head yet?
你那木瓜腦袋還沒搞清楚麼
I'm not walking anywhere!
我哪也不去！
Fine.
好吧
Sit in a crater. I've had enough of you anyway.
在坑裡坐著吧  反正我也受夠你了
I was gonna put you back in the sky once I'd brought you to my Victoria,
我本打算一把你送給 我的Victoria之後就送你回天上的
but clearly, you'd rather sit on your own in the middle of nowhere forever.
但很顯然  你寧願永遠坐在這  哪也不去
And just how were you planning to get me back to the sky?
只是你要怎麼送我回天上呢？
I find the fastest way to travel is by candlelight.
我知道最快速的移動方式  利用蠟燭的光
- You've got a Babylon candle. - Yeah, I have a bubbling candle.
- 你有一根巴比倫蠟燭 - Yeah  我有一根bubbling蠟燭
- A Babylon candle. - That's what I said.
- 是巴比倫蠟燭 - 我就是這麼說的
You said "Bubbling."
你說的是"bubbling"
Anyway, I was going to give what's left of it to you.
不管怎樣  我都會把剩下的給你
Well, that barely has one use left.
Well  這個已經用得沒剩多少了
So be grateful I'm not using it right now to get us both back to the wall.
你應該感激我現在不使用它 來使我們馬上回到牆那邊去
Unless you have a better way of getting yourself home.
除非你想到了回家的更好的辦法
Fine!
好吧！
Help me up.
扶我起來
All right. All right. I'm helping.
好的  好的  我正在扶
And you are gonna have to walk quicker than that.
你得再走快一點
Otherwise, I'll never get you back to Victoria in a week.
否則我就不能在一周內把你帶給Victoria
Don't push your luck.
不要推你的幸運星
Don't take less than a florin for him, Bernard! You understand?
2先令以下絕不能賣它  Bernard！聽明白嗎？
- Yes, Mother. - No dilly-dallying!
- Yes 母親 - 別磨磨蹭蹭的
And don't even think of stopping at the tavern, Bernard, or you'll be sorry!
還有  想都別想在酒館逗留 Bernard  否則你會後悔的
A florin for your goat, boy.
我出2先令買你的山羊 小夥子
Oh.
Oh
He's a bit small to pull your cart.
它小了點  拉不動你的車
You're quite right.
你說的完全正確
That's much better.
這樣就好多了
Bernard!
Bernard！
Get on!
快點
Who goes there?
來者何人？
What do you want with me, a poor old flower...
你要對我幹什麼？我只是個窮賣花的老太...
Oh, do shut up. I know what you are
Oh  快閉嘴  我知道你是什麼人
and I swear by the ordinances of the sisterhood to which we both belong
我以姐妹之情發誓你和我是一道的
that I mean you no harm this day.
今天我對你絕無惡意
I wish to share your meal.
我只是想分享你的美味
Well, one can never be too careful. Sit down. I'll get you a seat.
Well  防人之心不可無  坐下  我給你個位子
- Anything else? - Nope.
- 還要點別的？ - 不了
What's it to be?
要哪部分？
Heads or tails?
頭還是尾巴？
Heads.
頭
So, stranger,
那麼 陌生人
where are you headed off to on this fine day?
這麼好的天  你趕著去哪？
I seek a fallen star.
我正在找一顆墜落的星星
She fell not far from here.
她落在離這不遠處
And when I find her, I shall take my great knife
一旦讓我找到她  我會拔出我的大刀
and cut out her heart while she still lives.
在她還活著的時候挖出她的心臟
And the glory of our youth shall be restored.
這樣我們將青春重現
Fallen star?
墜落的星？
That's the best news I've had in ages.
對我這種年紀的人來說  這可是最好的消息了
I could do with losing a few years meself.
我可以讓自己變得再年輕點
So whereabouts did you...
那你知道她的下落...
Limbus grass!
異形草！
You dare to steal truth from my lips by feeding me limbus grass?
你竟敢用異形草來套我的話？
Do you have any idea what a big mistake you've made, Ditchwater Sal?
你知不知道自己犯了個多大的錯誤 Ditchwater Sal？
How do you know my...
你怎麼知道我的...
- Who are you? - Look again.
- 你是誰？ - 看清楚點
I shall not seek the star, Your Dark Majesty. I swear.
我不會去尋找那顆流星了  黑暗君主  我發誓
Seek all you wish.
你想找你就找吧
You shall not see the star, touch it, smell or hear it.
反正你將看不到、摸不到、 聞不到、也聽不到那顆流星
You will not perceive her even if she stands before you.
即使她站在你眼前  你也感覺不到她的存在
Pray you never meet me again, Ditchwater Sal.
祈禱你永遠不會再遇見我吧  Ditchwater Sal
Oh, right. So let me get this straight.
Oh  好吧  讓我來搞清楚
You think you know we're going the right way because...
你認為你知道我們走對了路  是因為...
And I quote, "I just do."
我引用你的話  "我就是知道"
I do, though. I don't know why.
沒錯  雖然我也不知為什麼
Maybe it's my love for Victoria guiding me home.
也許是我對Victoria的愛在指引我回家
- Please. - Yvonne, whether you like it or not...
- 拜託 - Yvonne  不管你喜不喜歡...
Yvaine! My name is Yvaine, so...
Yvaine！我的名字是Yvaine  那麼...
How many times do I have to...
我得跟你說多少遍...
Would you... Would you please slow down?
你就不能...就不能走慢點？
Yes, yes.
Yes   yes
Look, we're... We're going north, all right?
聽著  我們...我們正朝北走  對麼？
The wall's north.
那道牆在北邊
And if you look up in the sky, even during the day, you can see the...
如果你抬頭看天空  即使是在白天  你也能看見...
The evening star. That's so weird.
...夜晚的星星  這真奇怪
That's funny. Hilarious. My sides are splitting.
很有趣  很搞笑  我身子骨都快散架了
No, I'm being...
No  我只是在...
Wait that... That was you! Really?
等等  那...那是你  真的？
What... What are...
你...你在...
- What are you doing? - What does it look like I'm doing?
- 你在幹什麼？ - 我看起來像在幹什麼？
- Sitting down. I'm tired. - Please don't do this again.
- 坐下來 我累了 - 請別再這樣了
We agreed we'd stop off at the next village to eat and rest.
我們說好的  在下個村子才停下 吃點東西  休息一下
Come on, Tristan. It's midday.
拜託  Tristan  已經正午了
I never stay up this late! Just, please, let me sleep!
我從未這麼遲還不睡  就一會  求你了  讓我睡吧
Okay, you... Well, then I'll... You sleep. I'll go and get something to eat.
Okay  你...Well  那我去... 你睡覺  我去弄點吃的來
What are you doing?
你這是做什麼？
What does it look like I'm doing? I'm making sure you don't run away.
我看起來像是在做什麼？ 我在確保你不會逃跑
Your Highness, the soothsayer, as you requested.
殿下  按您的吩咐  我們把占卜者帶來了
South, you said.
向南方  你說過
South we went.
我們向南方走
Still no stone.
還是沒找到寶石
Do you now propose we start swimming?
你現在是否想建議我們去游泳？
Sire, I've merely relayed to you what the runes have told me.
陛下  我只是把占卜石告訴我的資訊轉達給您
I can do no more.
我僅能幫這些而已
Well, consult them again.
Well  那再占卜一次
Wait.
等等
Before we seek the stone, I have another question.
在我們問寶石的下落之前 我還有另外一個問題
Am I the seventh son?
我是不是第七個兒子？
Yes.
Yes
Another question.
另一個問題
Is my favorite color blue?
我最喜歡的顏色是不是藍色？
Yes.
Yes
Has excessive begging or pleading ever persuaded me
我曾經因低三下四的乞求和辯解 而饒恕過背叛者的性命嗎？
What does that mean?
這個意味著什麼？
- That means no. - Good.
- 這個意思是"no" - 很好
Throw them again. This time, throw them high.
再扔一次  這次扔高一點
Do you work for my brother?
你是為我哥哥工作的麼？
So, do we continue west?
那麼  我們繼續向西嗎？
Tristan?
Tristan？
Who's there?
誰在那？
Tristan, is that you?
Tristan  是你嗎？
It's not funny.
這一點都不好玩
Tristan?
Tristan？
Come on.
快來
Be careful how much magic you use, sister.
注意你用了多少魔法  姐姐
It's beginning to show.
開始顯現出來了
One goat and a small enchantment. Hardly extravagant.
一隻山羊和一些小魔法  這不算奢侈
Well, even using the ring will take its toll.
Well  即使用指環也會造成能量損失
Better you call on us only in dire need.
你最好只在急需時才召喚我們
And use your runes to locate the star yourself.
你自己用占卜石確定那顆星的位置
I used them and she should be here.
我用過占卜石  她本該在這兒的
But now they're just telling me gibberish.
但現在  這些占卜石只是在胡言亂語
It is because you must stay where you are, my sister.
那是因為你得呆在你現在地方  姐姐
She is coming to you.
她正朝你走來
Oh, be warned, Lamia. Delicacy is needed.
Oh  注意  Lamia  你得對她體貼點
Misery has drained her. She's barely shining.
她被痛苦糾纏  都快失去光澤了
Set a trap that ensures her heart is glowing before you cut it out.
設個圈套 以確保她的心在你挖出來之前還是生機勃勃的
Yvaine! Yvaine!
Yvaine！Yvaine！
Oh, you idiot.
Oh  你個蠢才
You shall become human.
你快變成人類了
You are Billy, the innkeeper. I am your wife, and you're our daughter.
你是Billy  旅館的主人 我是你妻子  而你是我們的女兒
Now, make everything ready. Our special guest will be here soon.
現在  一切準備好 我們特殊的客人很快就會到來了
I mean, who's to say he'd have even kept his promise about the candle?
我是說  誰能保證他會信守關於蠟燭的諾言呢？
I just refuse to believe he's the only person in Stormhold
我就不信他是Stormhold城裡 唯一一個能幫助我的人
Going on and on and on. Just "Victoria this" and "Victoria that."
不停地絮叨  就只會說Victoria長Victoria短的
Tristan?
Tristan？
Please protect our sister, Tristan.
請保護好我們的妹妹  Tristan
Yvaine is in grave danger.
Yvaine正處於極度危險中
The unicorn came to help her.
獨角獸趕去幫她了
But now they're heading into a trap.
但此刻他們正落入別人設下的圈套之中
No star is safe in Stormhold.
在Stormhold城沒有任何星是安全的
The last to fall, 400 years ago,
400年前  上次墜落的那顆星...
was captured by the same witches who seek Yvaine now.
...被那些女巫得到了 而現在她們又在尋找Yvaine
They tricked her,
她們會欺騙她
cared for her,
假裝關心她
and when her heart was once more aglow,
等到她的心臟再次發光時
they cut it from her chest
她們就會從她胸口挖出心臟來
and ate it.
並吃了它
There's no time to waste.
沒時間可浪費了
A coach is coming.
有輛馬車正在過來
By any means possible, you must get on it.
無論如何你都要搭上那輛馬車  這很重要
Run.
快跑
Whoa!
Whoa!
If Septimus insists on sending a boy to do a man's job...
- 如果Septimus堅持要派個孩子來做男人的活兒... - No  no  no  等一等  求你
I don't know a Septimus. I just need a lift.
我不認識叫Septimus的  我只想搭個便車
Look at me, look at me. I'm unarmed. Please.
看看我  看看我  我沒有武器  求求你
Please, let me ride with you.
請讓我和你一起走
I'm afraid that's impossible. I'm on a quest of enormous importance.
恐怕不行  我有重要的事情要辦
Well, then all the more reason to take me with you.
Well  那你更應該帶上我了
There may come a time when you need a second pair of hands. Sir?
沒准你什麼時候需要個副手  先生
Please. Maybe providence sent me to you just as it sent you to me.
拜託  也許是上天讓我遇見你 正如它讓你遇見我一樣
- Get on. - Oh, yes. Thank you.
- 上車 - Oh   yes  謝謝
Goodness me, my dear. Come in out of this wretched rain!
天哪  親愛的  快從那該死的雨裡進來吧
We have food and drink, a warm bed and plenty of hot water for a bath.
我們有食物和飲料  有溫暖的床 還提供充足的熱水供你洗澡
How do you like your bath? Warm, hot or boil-a-lobster?
你喜歡怎樣洗？溫水  熱水還是沸水？
I honestly don't know.
說實話  我也不知道
Then let me choose for you,
那就讓我來替你選擇吧
and I'll have my husband take your horse to the stable.
我會讓我丈夫把你的馬牽到馬廄去
Billy?
Billy？
Now, let's get you out of your wet things, shall we?
現在  把你這身濕衣服脫下來  好嗎？
Feeling better?
感覺好些了嗎？
Much. Thank you.
好多了 謝謝你
The warm water's actually done me a world of good.
暖水真的讓我感覺舒服極了
You see? The powers of a nice, hot bath.
知道了吧？熱水澡的威力就在這兒
And your leg? Any improvement?
你的腿呢？感覺好些了嗎？
That is extraordinary.
這太神奇了
It's the very least I could do. I'm just glad you're feeling better.
我只盡了自己的綿薄之力 很高興你感覺好點了
You seem happier in yourself, too.
你看起來也更快樂了
I do feel happier. Less troubled.
我確實感到更快樂了  煩惱則相應少了
Wonderful.
好極了
Nothing like a nice soak to warm the cockles of your heart.
沒有什麼能比泡熱水澡更能溫暖你的內心了
Now, I'm only a simple innkeeper's wife,
現在  我只是個善良旅館主人的妻子
but I've been told I have a healer's hands.
但人們說我有一雙可以幫人療養的手
I'd be glad to give you a massage.
我會很樂意幫你按摩一下
What's a massage?
什麼是按摩？
Never had... Well, bless my soul.
你從沒...Well...天佑我
Nothing like a massage to send you off for the finest and deepest night's sleep.
沒有什麼比按摩更能讓你睡得又香又甜
I do have trouble sleeping at night.
我晚上確實是很難入睡
Lie on your back, dear.
躺下吧  親愛的
Why not close your eyes?
為什麼不閉上眼睛？
You'll drift off better that way.
這樣的話你會更容易覺得飄飄欲仙
Hello!
Hello!
Service!
我們要住店！
Maybe we should carry on and try the next inn,
也許我們該繼續前進  試試下一家旅館
especially if this stone is as close as your runes say.
尤其是當我們如 占卜石所說的那樣離寶石很近的話
I'll give it one more try.
我再試一次
Relax here, my love.
放鬆  親愛的
I'll be back just as soon as I've taken care of this customer.
我一招呼好這位客人就馬上回來
At last. We require accommodation.
終於開門了  我們要住宿
Please help my friend take the horses to the stables.
請幫我的朋友把馬牽到馬廄去
Hello!
Hello!
Oh.
Oh
I'm accustomed to better service,
我習慣享用更好的服務
but you're awake now and that's what counts.
不過既然把你吵醒了  那就算吧
Prepare your best room.
給我準備最好的房間
- She got the stone. - Stone, stone.
- 她得到了寶石 - 寶石  寶石
I'll thank you not to bother my guest, sir. I am the lady of this inn.
請別打擾我的客人  先生  我是店主人
Glass of wine?
來杯葡萄酒？
No, no, no, no, no.
No  no  no  no  no
No.
No
Until my brother is dead, I have vowed to drink only my own wine.
在我兄弟死之前  我發誓只喝我自己的酒
Though my friend in the stables might be glad of a drop.
可能我那位在馬廄裡的朋友會樂意喝一杯
Your best room, perhaps?
準備好你們最好的房間嗎？
Of course.
當然
I'm sorry. I presumed that...
對不起  我猜你是...
Traveling alone, are you?
...獨自旅行  對嗎？
I've just stabled my four black stallions and my carriage.
我剛剛把我的四匹黑種馬和馬車送到馬廄裡去
Well, I say mine. It belonged to my late father.
Well  我說是我的 實際上它們屬於我已故的父親的
Thank you.
謝謝
That's so kind, thank you very much. My name's Tristan. What's yours?
你太好了  非常感謝你 我的名字叫Tristan  你呢？
Bernard.
Bernard
There was not a horse or beast he could not master.
沒有任何一匹馬或野獸是他不能駕禦的
So much so that in his youth, he took to riding a camel,
太多了以致於在他年輕的時候 他曾經騎過一頭駱駝
which was comical.
顯得非常滑稽
When he passed, the carriage came to me.
他死後  馬車就歸我了
She's got the stone!
她拿到了寶石
- She's got it!
- 她拿到了寶石！
And it's the largest in all of Stormhold, so they say.
這是Stormhold城最大的馬車  他們是這麼說的
How nice for you. If you'll excuse me.
對你來說這真好  抱歉  失陪一下
Wait.
等等
That stone you're wearing. It can't be.
你戴著那個寶石  不可能吧
- Oh, finally. - Yeah, good, well done, yes, sir.
- Oh  終於察覺到了 - Yeah  不錯  幹得好  yes  先生
- Well done. - Sweet.
- 幹得好 - 親愛的
Come here. Let me see it.
過來  讓我看看
You have no idea what you're meddling with.
你根本不知道你在管誰的閒事
I am Primus, the first born of Stormhold and I demand that you bring it to me!
我是Stormhold城的大王子Primus 我命令你把它拿來給我
Bring me the stone! Now!
把寶石給我  現在就給我！
Prince Primus! Don't touch anything they give you! They tried to...
Primus王子 她們給你的任何東西都別碰  她們想...
- Are you all right? - Billy!
- 你沒事吧？ - Billy！
Get him!
抓住他
The burning golden heart of a star at peace
你那弱小無力的心與處於平靜中的 火熱的金子般的星星之心比起來  不值一提
Even so, better than no heart at all.
儘管如此  也總比完全沒有心臟要好
Yvaine? Hold me tight and think of home.
Yvaine？緊緊抓著我  心裡想著家
No!
No!
- What the hell did you do? - What did I do? What did you do?
- 你到底做了些什麼？ - 我做了些什麼？應該問你做了些什麼？
"Think of home!" That was a great plan!
"想著家的樣子"  真是個好計畫
You thought of your home and I thought of mine
你想著你的家  而我想著我的家
and now we're halfway between the two!
而現在我們在兩個家的中間了！
Oh, you stupid cow! What did you think of your home for?
Oh  你這頭笨牛  你想著你的家幹什麼？
You just said "home"!
你只是說"家"！
If you wanted me to think of your home, you should have said!
如果你要我想你的家  那就該說清楚
Some crazy lady was going to cut your heart out
一個瘋女人想把你的心挖出來
and you wanted more specific instructions?
你還指望我能有時間說得更清楚？
Perhaps you'd like it in writing! Or a diagram, maybe!
或許你還要我把它寫下來！甚至畫個圖示！
Look, Captain Shakespeare! Caught ourselves a little bonus!
看  Shakespeare船長！ 我們抓到了這些戰利品
A couple of Lightning Marshals!
Lightning Marshals夫婦！
They don't look like Lightning Marshals to me.
在我看來  他們不像Lightning Marshals夫婦
Why else would anyone be up here in the middle of a storm?
為什麼會有其他人到這暴風雨的裡面來？
"Why else would anyone be up here in the middle of a storm?"
"為什麼會有其他人到這暴風雨的裡面來?"
Well, let's think.
Well  讓我們想想
Maybe for the same godforsaken reason we are!
也許是和我們一樣的荒唐理由
Now, who are you?
你們是誰？
Let's see if a night on our lovely brig will loosen their lips!
我們來看看 在我們可愛的禁閉室裡呆一晚是否能讓他們開口
- Get them in the brig! - You heard the man! Let's go!
- 把他們帶到禁閉室去！ - 你們聽見了嗎！快走
Get them into the brig and the rest of you dirty dogs, back to work!
把他們帶到禁閉室去 你們這群剩下的髒狗快回去幹活
We've got lightning to catch! Come on!
我們還要抓住閃電呢！快點！
- They're going to kill us, aren't they? - I don't know.
- 他們準備殺了我們的  是嗎？ - 我不知道
You know, it's funny. I used to watch...
你知道  這有點滑稽  我過去常常看...
I used to watch people having adventures.
我過去常常看人們進行冒險
I envied them.
我還嫉妒他們可以去冒險
You ever heard the expression, "Be careful what you wish for"?
你有沒有聽過"當心你所期待的"這種說法？
What? So ending up with my heart cut out, that'll serve me right, will it?
什麼？你是說以挖我的心來結束 是我罪有應得  對嗎？
No. No, I didn't... I didn't mean it like that.
No. No  我不是...我不是那個意思
Look, I admire you dreaming.
你看  我欽佩你能夠有夢想
Shop boy like me,
像我這樣的商店小子
I could never have imagined an adventure this big
我決不會想到為了實現願望要去做這麼大的冒險
I just thought I'd find some lump of celestial rock
我只是想  我會找到天上掉下的那塊石頭
and take it home, and that would be it.
並把它帶回家  就這樣
And you got me.
而你卻找到了我
If there's one thing I've learned in all my years watching Earth,
在我觀察地球的這麼多年來 如果要說一件我學到的事
it's that people aren't what they may seem.
那就是人們並不都是象他們表面看上去的那樣
There are shop boys
有些確實是商店小子
and there are boys who just happen to work in shops for the time being.
而有些人則只是碰巧暫時在雜貨店裡工作
And trust me, Tristan, you're no shop boy.
相信我  Tristan  你不是什麼商店小子
You saved my life. Thank you.
你救了我的命  謝謝你
Well, well, well.
Well   well   well
The last brother dead.
最後一個兄弟死了
Which means that I'm king.
也就是說我是國王了
I'm king!
我是國王！
Not yet, brother.
還不是  兄弟
Damn. I still need the stone.
該死  我還是要得到那塊寶石
- Your brother doesn't have it? - Well, why don't you find out?
- 你兄弟身上沒有嗎？ - Well  你為什麼不找找？
Where is my stone?
我的寶石在哪？
I don't...
我不...
The man, see, your brother... I heard him speak of a stone.
那個人  知道嗎？你的兄弟...我聽他提起過寶石
Yeah. The girl had it. The girl had it.
Yeah  它在那女孩手上  它在那女孩手上
- What girl? - I don't know.
- 什麼女孩？ - 我不知道
A girl. She got away. Because this was a trap set up for her,
一個女孩  她逃走了 因為這個圈套是為她而設計的
but your brother, he come just straight into it.
但你兄弟  他卻直接闖進這個圈套裡
A trap? Set by who?
一個圈套？誰設計的？
A woman you should pray you'll never meet.
一個你會祈禱永遠也別碰見的女人
She's...
她已經...
She's gone. She took your brother's carriage.
她已經走了  還帶走了你兄弟的馬車
This woman wanted my stone?
這個女人想要我的寶石嗎？
No. She wanted the girl's heart.
No  她想要那個女孩的心
She said the girl was a star and she wanted to cut out her heart and...
她說那個女孩是一顆星 她想挖出她的心臟  然後...
Eat it?
吃了它？
Oh, my God.
Oh  my God
Do you have any idea what this means?
你知道這意味著什麼嗎？
Everlasting life.
永恆的生命
King forever.
永遠的國王
It's not here, sire.
不在這裡  陛下
This idiot's coming with us.
這個白癡跟我們一起上路
- Ask again. - We have asked again
- 再問一遍 - 我們已經一再問過了
and the answer is still the same. She is airborne!
答案還是一樣的  她在空中飛著
Well, she can't remain so forever.
Well  她不能永遠呆在空中
Inform me as soon as she touches ground!
她一著陸就立刻通知我！
Lmmediately! Do you understand?
立刻！你們明白嗎？
Watch your tongue, sister! It is you and not we who've lost her.
注意你的語氣  姐姐  是你而不是我們失去她的
Lost her and broken the knife!
把她弄丟了  把刀也弄斷了！
Even if you apprehend her, how will you complete the deed?
即使你抓到了她  沒有刀你怎樣完成任務？
Perhaps you should return now and one of us set out in your place.
也許你該現在回來  由我們中的一個來代替你
Don't be absurd.
別發傻了
I'll bring her home and deal with her there.
我會把她帶回家  在那裡把她處理掉
Be sure everything is ready for our arrival.
確保在我們回來之前把一切準備妥當
Tell me about Victoria then.
給我講講Victoria的事吧
Well, she...
Well...她...
There's nothing more to tell you.
沒有什麼好跟你說的
Because the little I know about love is that it's unconditional.
因為我只知道愛情是沒有條件的
It's not something you can buy.
它不是什麼你能買得到的東西
Hang on. This wasn't about me buying her love.
等等  我並不是在買她的愛情
This was a way for me to prove how I felt.
我只是用這種方式來證明我對她的感覺
And what's she doing to prove how she feels about you?
那她又做了些什麼來證明她對你的感覺呢？
Well...
Well...
Look, Yvaine, you'll understand when you meet her. All right?
你瞧  Yvaine  當你見到她時你就會理解的  好嗎？
Provided we don't get murdered by pirates first.
前提是我們沒有被海盜殺死
Murdered by pirates. Heart torn out and eaten. Meet Victoria.
被海盜殺死  心臟被挖出來吃掉  認識Victoria
I can't quite decide which sounds more fun.
我完全決定不了哪個聽起來更有趣些
We've located the sky vessel.
我們已經確定飛星船的位置了
It's headed north for the port town on Mount Drummond
它正朝北飛向Drummond山上的港口小鎮
and you are no longer the only one seeking the star.
你們不再是唯一追尋那星星的人了
There's someone following your tracks!
有人正跟著你們的車轍！
A witch? A warlock?
一個女巫？還是一個男巫？
A prince and he's catching you up! Get a move on!
是位王子  他正在追趕你  行動快一點
So, this is the part where you tell me who you are and why you're up here.
那麼  你們就在這兒告訴我你們是誰 還有你們為什麼跑到天上來
Or I'll snap her pretty little fingers one by one like dry twigs!
否則我會擰斷她漂亮的小玉指 一根接一根  就像擰斷幹樹枝一樣
My name is Tristan Thorn.
我叫Tristan Thorn
- This is my wife, Yvaine. - Your wife?
- 這是我妻子Yvaine - 你妻子？
Far too young and radiant to belong to just one man!
這麼年輕這麼有氣質  只屬於一個男人太浪費了
It's share and share alike aboard my vessel, sonny boy!
在我的船上  東西是要大家分享的  小傢伙！
If you dare even touch her...
如果你膽敢碰她...
You may think you're showing a little spirit in front of your lady friend,
你可能以為你在自己的女人面前表現得很有骨氣
but if you talk back to me again, I'll feed your tongue to the dogs,
但如果你再用這種口氣跟我說話 我就把你的舌頭拿去喂狗
you impertinent little pup!
你這個無禮的小雜種！
- Sir? - Better! But still interrupting.
- 先生？ - 這好點  但仍然在打擾我說話
Let's see. A hanging's always good for morale!
讓我們看看  絞刑總是對鼓舞士氣很有好處！
Maybe we'll watch you dance a gallows jig!
也許我們能看到你跳一段絞刑快步舞
Or perhaps I'll just tip you over the side and have done with it!
又或許我就把你直接扔出艙外了事
It's a very long way down.
距離地面還有很長一段距離
Plenty of time to reminisce about your pitifully short lives.
你有足夠的時間去回憶一下你可憐的短暫人生
Please, look, we're just trying to make our way home,
求你了  你瞧  我們只是想回家
back to a place called Wall, where I come from.
回到一個叫做Wall的地方  我就是從那兒來的
What did you say?
你說什麼？
I said we were trying to get home to Wall.
我說我們只是想回家  回到Wall鎮
That's one lie too many, my son.
休想騙我  孩子
- Wall? - Shut up.
- Wall鎮？ - 閉嘴
What's he saying?
他在說什麼？
Thought you could just wander onto my patch, did you?
你以為可以在我的地盤上放肆  是嗎？
- He is. Yeah, he's gonna... - And live to tell the tale?
- 是的  Yeah  他要... - 還想睜著眼說瞎話？
All right, go, on the deck, on the deck, on the deck! Now, go, go, go!
好吧  到甲板上去  到甲板上去 到甲板上去  馬上  快！快！快！
Big mistake, Mr. Thorn! And the last one you'll ever make!
你犯大錯誤了  Thorn先生 這也將是你犯的最後一個錯誤
- No! No! You brute! - Come... Come on!
- No! No!  你這個畜生！ - 快...快點
- You murderer! You pig! - Come on! Get up! Get up!
- 你這個兇手！你這頭豬！ - 快點！起來！起來！
I'm taking the girl to my cabin, and mark my words,
我要把這個女孩帶到我的船艙  還有聽清楚了
anyone who disturbs me for the next few hours
在接下來的幾個小時裡  任何打擾我的人...
- will get the same treatment! - What? You'll...
- ...都將得到相同的下場 - 什麼？你要...
No, you idiot! I'll sling you over the side as well!
No  你這個白癡！小心我把你也扔下去！
Oh, yeah.
Oh  yeah
Captain's busy. So should you be.
船長很忙  所以你們應該閃開
Get in there, wench!
進去  蕩婦！
So, that went well, I thought.
那麼  戲演得不錯吧  我想
Now, tell me news of my beloved England.
現在  告訴我關於我心愛的England的最新消息
I want to hear absolutely everything.
我要聽到一切的事
Hang on. I can't believe your crew fell for that.
等一下  我真不敢相信 你的全體船員就那樣被騙過去了
And where in God's name did you get that mannequin from?
以上帝的名義  你是從哪變出那具人體模型來的？
Oh, it works every time.
Oh  每次都很管用
An ounce of bargaining, a pinch of trickery,
小討價還價一下  加上一點點詭計
a soupcon of intimidation, et voila!
再加一小點威嚇  你們瞧
The perfect recipe for a towering reputation
不需要流一滴血又能獲得傑出聲望的絕妙方法
Ever try to get blood stains out of a silk shirt? Nightmare.
試過把血跡從絲綢衣服上洗掉嗎？簡直是惡夢
Right. I still don't understand how they won't recognize me.
是啊  我還是不明白為什麼他們沒認出我來
Tristan, dear boy, when I'm done,
Tristan  親愛的孩子  當我幹完後
your own mother won't recognize you.
連你的親生母親都認不出你來
Now, we've no time to waste.
現在我們沒時間可浪費了
We have only two hours before we make port.
在我們抵達港口之前只剩兩小時
First and foremost...
首先的也是最重要的...
It'll be so good to see you out of those dreary clothes.
能看到你們把這身噁心的衣服脫掉就再好不過了
So very small-town errand-boy. Howlingly parochial.
如此一個小鎮的男僕  真寒酸
Here. Tres you.
來  穿上試試
I wore it as a younger man. I hate to throw anything away.
是我年輕時穿  我不喜歡亂扔東西
You know the day you do, it'll come back in fashion,
你們知道的  總有一天這款式會重新流行
be oh, so de la mode.
就又成為時尚(法語)
Now, you, darling.
至於你  親愛的
I have some lovely dresses. Take your pick.
我有些可愛的裙子  隨便挑吧
Oh, no, really, I'm fine.
Oh  no  真的  我的很好
Honey, you're wearing a bathrobe.
Honey  你穿的是浴袍
Now, England, England. I want to hear everything.
現在  England  England  我想知道所有的事
- You're not from England. - Oh, no, sadly, no.
- 你不是從England來的 - Oh  no  很可惜  no
But from my earliest youth, I lapped up the stories.
不過在我很小的時候我就已經啃光那些故事了
People always told me they were nothing more than folklore,
人們總是跟說我那些都只不過是民間傳說而已
but my heart told me they were true.
但我內心卻告訴我它們是真的
As a boy, I'd scurry away from my father at the market
在我還是個孩子的時候 經常在市場從我父親身邊跑掉
while he did his deals just to peek over the wall,
當他做著買賣時  我就偷偷地去看牆那邊
dream of, perhaps, crossing it one day, seeing England for myself.
夢想著可能會有一天我能越過它 親眼看看England
Really? So you... You were here looking over there.
真的？那麼你...人在這邊卻想著那邊
Oh, yes.
Oh   yes
- Hair. - Hair?
- 頭髮 - 頭髮？
Mind you, I did my best to fit in.
請注意了  我盡最大努力來扮演我的角色
Tried to make my father, Captain Ghostmaker, proud.
試圖來繼承我父親Ghostmaker船長的輝煌
Forged a decent reputation as a ruthless marauder
打造一個殘忍掠奪者和冷血殺手的體面名聲
But my father died.
不過我父親已經去世了
I always promised him I'd take over the family business,
我總是答應他繼承家族事業
keep the old girl flying.
讓這艘舊船繼續飛翔
You have no idea the lightness it brings to my heart
你們不會知道能夠一吐心扉時我多麼高興
being able to confide in you charming young people.
能對你兩位可愛的年輕人盡情傾訴
The pressure of maintaining the whole Captain Shakespeare persona
為了全體船員的利益  我得忍受維持 Shakespear船長形象的壓力  我不知道該怎麼說
Sometimes...
有時...
You see, I'm very much a man of my own creation.
你們明白  我只是活在自己世界裡的人
Even chose the name specially. Took me ages.
甚至專門選擇這個名字  幾十年苦心打造它
See, I'm thinking legendary British wordsmith.
你們看  在我想著著名的British作家之時
My enemies and crew are thinking, "Shake! Spear!"
我的敵人們和船員們卻在想"沖啊！殺啊"
It's little things like that make me happy.
像這樣的小事情總能讓我高興點
I don't understand that.
我不太明白
Surely it would make you happier just to be yourself.
顯然你做回你自己就會感到更快樂
Why fight to be accepted by people you don't actually want to be like?
為什麼你要勉強自己成為你自己 根本不想當的那種人來讓人們接受呢？
Yeah. Why would anyone do that to himself?
Yeah  為什麼要對自己那麼做呢？
Exactly.
確實是
Port ahoy! Ready the lightning barrels!
嘿  港口  準備好幸運桶裝酒來迎接我們！
Hurry up.
快點
Yeah. Doesn't seem very fresh. I'll be honest.
Yeah  看起來不是太新鮮  我不會出高價的
Shall I give you a little taste, young Ferdinand?
要不要我讓你嘗一嘗  年輕的Ferdinand？
No, no. Oh, there you go.
- No  no  Oh - 看那邊
Brilliant. Like they're cheap.
妙極  它們只是象劣質貨
I think it's still crackling, very much alive, still tres fresh.
我想它仍活蹦亂跳生機勃勃的  仍然很新鮮
- So, name your best price. - For 10,000 bolts?
- 那麼  開個實價來 - 10000匹布？
Ten thousand bolts of finest quality grade A.
最好的A等級的10000匹布
Yeah, but it's difficult to shift, isn't it? Difficult to store.
Yeah  但它們很難轉移  不是麼？也很難存放
If I get the Revenue Men in here sniffing round, what's the...
如果我把稅務官叫來聞一圈  那可就...
Best price, 150 guineas.
這個價  150金幣
Gentlemen, put the merchandise back onboard and prepare to sail.
先生們  把貨物放回船上準備起航
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. - Ferdinand, always a pleasure.
- Whoa   whoa   whoa - Ferdinand   總是這麼高興
Hold on. Hold on. One minute. Hold on, cuddles.
等下  等下 就一小會  等下  哥們
- Oh, he's... - One-sixty. One-sixty.
- 哦  他... - 160吧  160金幣
Seeing as I'm feeling particularly generous today,
你看  今天我可算是非常慷慨的了
I'll settle for 200.
200金幣就給你了
Two hundred? Okay. You're having a laugh.
200金幣？Okay  你在開玩笑嗎？
Have you had your head in that?
你把你的腦袋塞進去了嗎？
Has he been sailing up where the air's too thin?
難道他在空氣稀薄的地方航行太久而大腦缺氧？
- You're being very rude. - Not anymore.
- 你太無禮了 - 不會再說了
- Two hundred. - One-eighty.
- 200 - 180
- That's not negotiation.
- 你還真是一條筋哦
I'm changing my number. One-eight-five.
我就讓一步  185
- Did I hear 200? - From you, you did. Yeah.
- 你說200了嗎？ - 是你  是你說的  Yeah
- You said 200. - Lf I did, you're a ventriloquist.
- 你說了200了 - 如果我說了  那就是你用腹語模仿我說的
Okay, one-nine-five. Final offer.
Okay  195  不能再高了
One-nine-five it is. So, with sales tax, that's, let's see, 200.
就195吧  那麼加上成交稅就是...我算算...200
Brilliant. Put it in the back.
算你狠  抬到後面去吧
Unbelievable. Here.
難以置信  過來
Yes? Can I help you?
Yes? 需要幫忙嗎?
Nosy.
多管閒事
Have you heard any of these rumors going round about a fallen star?
你有在附近聽說過關於一顆墜星的傳言嗎？
Everyone's talking about it.
每個人都在談論它
You get your hands on one of them, we can shut up shop. Retire.
如果我們能得到它   我們就可以退休養老了
- Fallen star? - Yeah.
- 墜星？ - Yeah
- Nothing on your travels? - No.
- 在你們旅途中沒有碰到？ - No
Not even a little sniff of a whisper?
- 連一點蛛絲馬跡都沒有？
Everyone's going on about it down at the market.
市場裡的每個人都在談論這個
Which market? The market near the wall?
哪個市場？靠近Wall鎮的那個嗎？
Yeah.
Yeah
Well, Ferdy, you're wasting your time listening to gossip
Well  Ferdy  你真是在浪費你的時間 居然會去聽那邊那群鳥人同行們散播的流言蜚語
- Well, if it... - Oh, my word! Speak of the devil.
- Well  如果它... - Oh  我的嘴  在胡說呢
Oh, yeah? What were you saying, then?
Oh   yeah? 那麼你們在說什麼呢？
Oh, what a wonderful woman you are, Sal.
Oh  你是個多麼不尋常的女士啊  Sal
How the world wouldn't be the same place without you.
沒有了你這世界就完全是另一個樣子了
You look great. You've had your feet done, haven't you?
你氣色挺好  你的腳好了  是麼？
But, you two, you have business to attend to. Sal. Ferdy. Good day.
你倆還有生意要談吧  Sal  Ferdy  祝過得順心
Come on. I've got something new for you.
來  我要給你看樣東西
Captain Shakespeare.
Shakespeare船長？
Stand down!
冷靜！
Meet my nephew, the fearsome buccaneer,
認識一下我的侄子  令人生畏的海盜
Tristan Thorn.
Tristan Thorn
He'll be joining us for our journey home.
他將和我們一起回去
I have the perfect gift to keep you amused on the way.
我送份大禮給你  讓你在路上玩得開心
Oh...
Oh...
Right, you lazy dogs!
向右  你們這群懶狗
Let's get young Tristan on his way home!
讓我們年輕的Tristan回家吧！
Touche.
不賴嘛
I'm impressed.
我真服了你了
Yvaine, I know what you are.
Yvaine  我知道你的底細了
No, no. Have no fear.
No   no  不用害怕
No one on this vessel will harm you, but there are plenty who would.
在這艘船上沒人會傷害你  但外面不是
Your emotions give you away, Yvaine. You must learn to control them.
你的情緒洩露了你的身份  Yvaine 你要學會控制它們
You've been glowing more brightly every day,
你每天都逐漸變得更燦爛
and I think you know why.
我想你知道為什麼會這樣
Of course I know why I'm glowing. I'm a star.
我當然知道我為什麼變得燦爛  我是顆星星
- And what do stars do best? - Well, it's certainly not the waltz.
- 星星最擅長的是什麼？ - Well  很顯不是跳waltz舞
- Now try. - Okay.
- 試一下 - Okay
- See? - Very good.
- 怎樣？ - 非常好
Due west, you say?
你說他們朝西去了？
And you're certain he had a girl with him?
你確定還有個女孩跟他在一起？
Yeah.
Yeah
You're sure? Absolutely sure? Sure you're not lying?
你確定？完全確定？確定你沒有撒謊？
I'd cross my heart if I had one.
如果我說謊我會讓它穿過我的心臟
- Brilliant. - You'd better be telling the truth,
- 很好 - 你最好說的是實話
you two-faced dog.
你這個兩面狗
I can get you one of them, actually. Very good guard dogs.
其實我能幫你抓到他們中的一個 很好用的看門狗
They can watch the back and the front door at the same time.
它們可以同時看到前方和後面
I can get you anything you want.
你想要什麼我都可以幫你弄到
What are the chances of getting a Babylon candle?
我有多大把握能得到巴比倫蠟燭？
That one's slim.
那就比較渺茫
Although, I did know a girl once, if you know what I mean...
不過  我倒是知道一個女孩得到過 如果你明白我意思的話...
I'm a ladies' man.
我有很多女人
...who had a sister...
這女孩有個姐姐...
I think it was a woman.
至少我認為是個女的
Oh, she was terrible. Face like a bag of frogs. Ugly frogs.
Oh  她長得恐怖極了 像癩蛤蟆一樣  還是很醜的那種
Enough.
夠了
Hold on tight! The Captain's at the helm!
抓緊了  船長在掌舵
So there's the road you'll need for Wall.
那就是通往Wall鎮的路
Good luck on your journey home, Yvaine, wherever that may be.
祝你們一路順風  Yvaine  不管要面對什麼
And good luck to you, Tristan, with your Victoria.
也祝你好運  Tristan  還有你的Victoria
Oh, how can we ever thank you enough for your kindness?
Oh  我都不知道該如何感謝你的慷慨相助了
Don't mention it. No, seriously, don't mention it.
別客氣  No  真的  無需客氣
Reputations, you know. A lifetime to build, seconds to destroy.
你知道  好名聲是要用一輩子去打造的 而摧毀則只需幾秒鐘
Oh, and Tristan, just remember...
Oh  Tristan  記牢...
Just think about it.
仔細想想吧
Well, give my regards to England. It's been a pleasure to meet you both.
Well  代我向England致敬  很高興見到你們倆
Mind you don't wear that wench out, Captain Tristan!
注意可別讓那蕩婦把你累著了  Tristan船長！
What did he say to you?
他對你說什麼了？
What did he say when?
他什麼時候說什麼了？
Just then. When he whispered to you.
就剛剛  他跟你悄悄話來著
No... No, he... He was just saying we should use the lightning
No...No  他...他只是說我們應該利用閃電光
to get you a Babylon candle.
來給你弄根巴比倫蠟燭
Barter for it, you know.
最好這樣做  你明白吧
For the last time, where is the girl?
最後問一遍  那個女孩在哪？
The girl with the stone! Where did she go?
帶著寶石的女孩！她去哪了？
- Are you mocking me? - No...
- 你在耍我麼？ - No...
'Cause if you are, believe me, you have seconds to live!
因為如果你在耍我 相信我  你馬上就得去見閻羅
What a freak.
簡直是怪物
Clean this thoroughly.
清洗乾淨  徹底點
Bollocks.
Bollocks
If you have quite finished squandering your magic
如果你已經在你那糟糕的臉蛋上糟蹋完魔法的話
you might like to know that the star has returned.
你會很高興聽到那星星已經回來了
She's back on land.
她回到地面了
I know, damn it. I couldn't reach the lake in time.
我知道  真該死  我沒能及時趕到湖邊
No matter. We have found her. She is on the road to the village of Wall.
沒關係  我們已經發現她了 她正在去Wall鎮的路上
If you take the shortcut across the marshes,
如果你抄小道穿過那片沼澤
you should arrive in time to intercept her.
你就能及時趕到把她攔住
Yvaine.
Yvaine
- Are you trying to break my leg again? - I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- 你又想把我的腿弄斷嗎？ - 對不起  對不起
I just... I can't risk people seeing you. I don't trust anyone.
我只是...我不能冒險讓別人發現你 我不相信任何人
But at this rate, if we keep stopping...
但是按現在的速度  如果我們老是停下...
Yvaine. We're making good time. Just leave it a minute.
Yvaine  我們在等好時機  就等一會就會有了
Aren't you tempted?
你受不住誘惑了吧？
Tempted? By what?
誘惑？被什麼誘惑？
Lmmortality.
永生不死
Let's say it wasn't my heart.
假如這不是我的心
Not me. Just a star you didn't know.
不是我  只是顆你不認識的星星
You seriously think I could kill anyone?
你真的認為我會隨便殺人嗎？
I mean, even if I could... Everlasting life?
我是說  即使是為了得到永恆生命？
I imagine it would be kind of lonely.
我想那反而會非常孤獨
Well,
Well
maybe if you had someone to share it with.
或者如果有個人跟你一起分享呢？
Someone you love.
一個你所鍾愛的人
Maybe then it might be different.
那可能就會不一樣了
Come on, I think we're safe.
來吧  我想現在安全了
Now remember, Captain Shakespeare has a fearsome reputation.
記住  Shakespeare船長有個非常可怕的名聲
- What the hell is this? - What are you doing here?
- 這是怎麼回事？ - 你在這裡幹什麼？
My name is Prince Septimus.
我是Septimus王子
And you're going to tell me where I can find the girl.
你必須告訴我在哪裡能找到那個女孩
All right, twinkletoes. I'm gonna count to three. One, two...
好吧  小古怪  我會數到三...一...二...
You know, you sort of glitter sometimes. I just noticed it. Is it normal?
你知道  有時你會閃一閃光 我剛注意到  是正常現象嗎？
Let's see if you can work it out for yourself.
讓我們看看你能不能自己想出來
What do stars do?
星星是做什麼的？
Attract trouble?
惹麻煩？
That's... All right, I'm sorry. Wait, I'm sorry.
那是...好吧  對不起  等等  對不起啦
All right, let me... Let me... Do I get another guess?
好吧  我來...我來...我再猜一次
Is it... Do they know exactly how to annoy a boy called Tristan Thorn?
那是...他們明確知道怎樣 使一個叫Tristan Thorn的男孩困擾嗎？
- How long will that take? - Maybe two days.
- 要走幾天？ - 可能兩天吧
But we don't have two days. Victoria's birthday is tomorrow.
但我們沒有兩天時間了 明天就是Victoria的生日
Yes, it is. Well remembered.
Yes  是啊  記性可真好啊
- Nice cup of Earl Grey. - Get out, everybody. Get out.
- 一杯美味的伯爵綠茶 - 滾出去  全給我滾出去
Did he hurt you, Captain?
他傷著你了嗎  船長？
Did you tell him where your nephew and the girl went?
你告訴他你的侄子和那個女孩去哪了嗎？
So what's the problem?
那到底怎麼回事？
It's my reputation.
是關於我的名聲
No. No, no. Don't be silly. Nonsense.
No  No  no  別發傻了  無需擔心
It's all right, Captain.
沒事的  船長
We always knew you were a whoopsie.
我們都知道你喜歡男扮女裝
- You'll always be our captain, Captain. - Aye, aye, Captain.
- 您永遠是我們的船長  船長 - 是呀  是呀  船長
Captain.
船長
Yeah. Let's go, let's go.
Yeah  我們出去  我們出去
Prince Septimus, your men, they're dead.
Septimus王子  你的手下都死光了
Oh, really?
Oh  是嗎？
Go on!
走！
I met that woman. She's friends with the Captain.
我見過那個女的  她是船長的朋友
He said she trades at the market near Wall.
他說她在Wall鎮附近的市場做生意的
- We could hitch a lift. - Really? She's a friend of the Captain's?
- 我們能搭順風車 - 真的麼？她是船長的朋友？
- You sure? - Yes, yes.
- 你確定？ - Yes  yes
Wait! Sorry! My name is Tristan Thorn. This...
等等！不好意思  我是Tristan Thorn  這是...
That's my flower.
那是我的花
Eighteen years I've been looking for that.
18年來我一直在找它
Give it to me now!
快把它還給我！
How dare you? That was a gift from his mother!
你怎麼敢這樣？那是他母親給他的禮物
Oh.
Oh
Perhaps I was mistaken.
或許我弄錯了
It's all right.
沒關係
It's obviously very valuable to you, so you can have it
顯然它對你來說非常有價值  我可以把它給你
in exchange for what I need.
作為交換  你得幫我個忙
- A Babylon candle? - And safe passage to the wall.
- 一根巴比倫蠟燭？ - 以及安全抵達Wall鎮
A Babylon candle?
一根巴比倫蠟燭？
Oh, no, no, no. I don't deal in black magic.
Oh  no  no  no  我不做涉及黑暗魔法的交易
Really?
是嗎？
Well, can you give us a lift then? To the wall?
Well  那你能讓我們搭順風車嗎？去Wall鎮？
Well, why didn't you say so in the first place?
Well  為什麼你不早說呢？
For that flower, I can offer you passage.
為了那朵花  我可以載你一程
- Food and lodging on the way? - Safe passage.
- 還需要準備路上的食宿嗎？ - 旅途安全就行
I swear that you will arrive at the wall
我發誓把你完整無缺、安全無恙的送到Wall鎮
Do you have any idea what manner of thing it was that you had?
你知道你身上的這朵花是什麼東西嗎？
Some kind of lucky charm?
某種幸運符咒？
A very lucky charm indeed. Protection.
確切地說  非常幸運的符咒  護身符
In fact, the exact same thing that would've prevented me from doing this.
事實上  這東西制止了我這樣做
- Oh, my God! What did you do? - Much better.
- Oh  天哪！ 你都幹了什麼？ - 好多了
You shall not see the star, touch it, smell or hear it.
你將看不到、摸不到、 聞不到、也聽不到那顆星星
Though I'll keep me word. You shall not be harmed.
我會遵守諾言  你不會受到傷害的
There. Food and lodging just as I promised.
進去吧  食宿就和我保證的一樣
Would I be correct in thinking that you can neither see nor hear me?
你看不見我也聽不見我說話  我說的對嗎？
Then I'd like to tell you that you smell of pee.
那麼我得告訴你  你聞起來一身尿味
You look like the wrong end of a dog.
你看上去像是一隻癩皮狗
And I swear, if I don't get my Tristan back as he was,
而且我發誓  要是Tristan不變回原形
I'll be your personal poltergeist!
我就會永遠在你身邊搗亂！
Tristan?
Tristan？
If you can understand me, look at me now.
如果你能聽懂我說話  就看著我
You know when I said I knew little about love?
你知道那時候我曾說過我對愛情不太懂
Well, that wasn't true.
Well  我其實在撒謊
I know a lot about love.
關於愛情我懂得很多
I've seen it. I've seen centuries and centuries of it.
我瞭解它  數個世紀以前我就瞭解它了
And it was the only thing that made watching your world bearable.
它是唯一能支撐我繼續關注人類世界的東西
All those wars. Pain and lies. Hate.
所有的那些戰爭、痛苦、謊言、仇恨
Made me want to turn away and never look down again.
使我很想轉過頭去  不再往下看
But to see the way that mankind loves.
但是我看到了人類相愛的方式
I mean, you could search the furthest reaches of the universe
我想說  就算找遍全宇宙...
and never find anything more beautiful.
也找不到比愛情更美好的東西了
So, yes, I know that love is unconditional.
所以  yes  我知道愛是無條件的
But I also know it can be unpredictable,
但我也知道愛也是無法預料的
unexpected, uncontrollable, unbearable
突如其來的  不可控制的  難以忍耐的
and, well, strangely easy to mistake for loathing.
還有  well  奇怪的是  也很容易會因愛成恨
And
...還有...
what I'm trying to say, Tristan, is
我想說的是...Tristan...是
I think I love you.
我想我愛上你了
My heart, it feels like my chest can barely contain it.
我的心  感覺就好像我的胸膛已經遏制不住它了
Like it doesn't belong to me anymore. It belongs to you.
就好象它不再屬於我  而是屬於你了
And if you wanted it, I'd wish for nothing in exchange.
如果你想要它  我會無償地把它獻給你
No gifts, no goods, no demonstrations of devotion.
無需禮物  無需金錢  無需奉獻式的證明
Nothing but knowing you love me, too.
只要能知道你也愛我就足夠了
Just your heart
我只要你的心...
in exchange for mine.
...來換取我的心
The wall is one mile that way.
從這兒再走一英里就到牆邊了
There. Though the walk might take you a little longer than normal.
那裡  雖然路程也許會讓你比平時多花一點時間
Transformation tends to leave the brain a bit scrambled for a while.
變回原形後  你的頭腦會發暈一段時間
You...
你...
Oh!
Oh!
I warned you. Save your strength.
我警告過你了  省點力氣吧
I've been so worried about you.
我擔心死你了
Victoria.
Victoria
I think I preferred "Mother."
我寧願你叫我"母親"
Come on. There's an inn over there. Victoria's birthday's not till tomorrow.
起來吧  那邊有家小旅館 Victoria的生日要明天才到
I think you need a bath and a good night's sleep
在你把我作為禮物送給她之前 我想你需要洗個好澡以及美妙的睡上一覺
Come on. Come.
來吧  來
- Come on, Tristan. It's not that far. - Okay.
- 來吧  Tristan  沒多遠了 - Okay
- Excuse me? - Oh!
- 打擾一下？ - Oh!
- I think you're in my bath. - Well, close your eyes!
- 我想你躺在我的浴缸裡了 - Well  快閉上眼睛
I'm not... Honestly, I'm not looking. Here, I'll turn away.
我沒有...老實說 我什麼也沒看到  你看  我轉過身了
All right, you can open them now.
好了  你可以睜眼了
Did you really mean what you said in the caravan?
你在馬車上說的話是真心的嗎
What I...
我說的...
But... But you were a mouse!
可... 可是你當時是只老鼠
You were a mouse! You wanted cheese! You didn't...
你是只老鼠啊！你只想要乳酪！你不應該...
I asked you to give me a sign.
我讓你給我個回應的
And risk you being too embarrassed to keep saying such lovely things?
要我冒令你感到尷尬而不再傾訴愛意 的風險(來給你回應)嗎？
You want to know what the Captain really whispered to me that day?
你想知道那天船長跟我耳語時真正說的是什麼嗎？
He told me that my true love was right in front of my eyes.
他告訴我  我的真愛就在我的眼前
And he was right.
他說得對
Hey, guys! Guys, come on! Come on, you got to come up and see this!
Hey  夥計們  夥計們 快來快來  你們快過來看看這個
No, thank you.
No  謝謝
- Pervert! - Suit yourself.
- 變態！ - 隨你的便
- Ironic, isn't it? - Yeah. What is?
- 真有點諷刺  不是麼？ - Yeah  你說什麼？
Septimus will be here by the morning,
Septimus明早就會來到這裡
find the girl, get the stone and be king forever.
找到這個女孩  得到寶石  永遠成為國王
So unjust.
太不公平了
Still, at least we will be free.
雖然如此  至少我們會自由了
You're very close. She's in the market town.
你離她很近了  她就在那個集市小鎮裡
One mile from the gap in the wall.
離那道牆的缺口只有一英里
You speak as if this is good news.
你說得就像這是個好消息似的
Do I need to remind you that Wall is not part of our universe?
要我提醒你嗎？ Wall鎮那邊根本不屬於我們這個世界
If she crosses the threshold into the human realm,
如果她穿過石牆入口、進入人類領地
our star becomes nothing more than a pitted lump of metallic rock.
我們的星星就會變成一團坑坑窪窪的金屬塊
Then I suggest you hurry up!
那麼我建議你快點！
What?
怎麼啦？
Oh, what do you want?
Oh  你想要什麼？
Sorry. Can I have a piece of paper and a pen?
對不起  能給我一張紙和一隻筆嗎？
Ask me again at a more reasonable hour.
另找一個更合適的時間再來問我吧
No, I can't. I have to go.
No  不行  我現在就得走了
Look, if my friend wakes up before I get back,
這樣吧  如果的我朋友在我回來前就醒來了
- please, can you give her a message? - Go on.
- 可否請你給我帶個口信給她？ - 說吧
You know, that's the first time I've ever slept at night.
你知道嗎  這是我第一次在夜裡睡著
I can't believe it.
真是難以置信
Tristan?
Tristan？
Have you seen my friend?
你看到我朋友了嗎？
He left absurdly early.
他一大早就很奇怪的出去了
He left?
他走了？
He told me to tell you he's gone to see Victoria
他讓我告訴你他要去見Victoria
because he's sorry, but he's found his true love
因為他覺得愧疚  但他已經找到了真愛
and he wants to spend the rest of his life with her.
並想跟她共度餘生
What?
什麼？
- Are you sure? - I'm positive.
- 你確定嗎？ - 完全確定
Hey! Hey, wait! Wait!
Hey! Hey  等等！等一下！
Happy birthday.
生日快樂
Tristan.
Tristan
What happened to you?
你怎麼啦？？
I found the star.
我找到了那顆星星
I can't believe you did it.
我簡直不敢相信你做到了
Where's my star? Can I see it?
我的星星在哪裡？我能看看嗎？
- Is it beautiful? - Yes.
- 漂亮嗎？ - Yes
Well, it's awfully small.
Well  怎麼小得這麼可憐
Well, that's just a little piece. A token for your birthday.
Well  這只是其中的一小塊 作為你生日的紀念品
Well... Well, then forget about the star.
Well... Well  忘掉星星的事情吧
It's not the star that I want.
我想要的並不是星星
You know what I want.
你知道我想要的是什麼
Yeah. I do.
Yeah  我知道
You want to grow up and get over yourself.
你想變得成熟  克服自我
- Humphrey. - Thorn.
- Humphrey - Thorn
You must have a death wish.
你一定是想死了
Humphrey. Humphrey, it's all right.
Humphrey  Humphrey  沒關係的
She's all yours.
她是你的人了
You really are a perfect couple. The best of luck to you both.
你們簡直是天造地設的一對  我衷心祝福你們
Well, why would I want this? It's just a measly handful of stardust!
Well  那我要這個來幹什麼？ 這只是一把微不足道的星塵！
Yvaine?
Yvaine？
She can't cross the wall.
她不能越過那堵牆
Go on!
沖啊！
Stop! Stop! If you go through there, you'll die!
站住！站住！你一跨過去就會死的！
What?
什麼？
If you set foot on human soil, you'll turn to rock.
你一踏上人類的土地  你就會變成石頭
Wretched slattern! Where have you taken me?
你這個卑鄙的賤女人  你想把我帶去哪裡？
Planning to enter Wall, were you?
你是想越過那道牆  是嗎？
If death is what you wish, my dear, I'd be more than happy to assist you.
如果你想找死  親愛的  我非常樂意幫你
Are you talking to me?
你是在跟我說話嗎？
You. Small world.
又是你  世界還真小
Anyhow, no, I wasn't. I was talking to the star.
總之  no  我不是和你說話 我是在和星星說話
What star?
什麼星星？
My slave girl's no star. Any fool can see that.
我的女僕可不是什麼星星 就連傻子都看得出來
If she was, I'd have had the heart out of her chest
如果她是的話 我一早就會挖出她的心臟了  相信我
Trust you? Not a mistake I'd be likely to make again.
相信你？我可不會再犯同樣的錯誤了
What's it to be, Ditchwater Sal? Heads or tails?
你想怎麼死  Ditchwater Sal？ 砍頭還是砍尾巴？
- Oh, God. Time to go. - She's not going anywhere.
- Oh  天哪！該走了 - 她哪都不去
I think you'll find she is.
我想你會發現她會去的
It's all right. You can come, too.
沒關係  你也可以一起去
You can ride in the carriage or be dragged behind it. Your choice.
你們是要乖乖上車 還是要被拖在馬車後面  自己選吧
What happened?
發生什麼事？
Be my guest. I quit.
請便吧  我不幹了
Eighty years I've stopped you people going out.
我已經在這裡守護了80年不讓人們出去
What I should have been worrying about
其實我真正該擔心的...
was those people from the other side coming in.
應該是那些從另一邊來的人
All right, just tell me what happened!
好吧  快告訴我發生什麼事了！
What happened? Oh, where to start?
發生了什麼事？Oh  從哪說起呢？
No!
No!
Come on!
快！
Go on!
快走！
The star!
那顆星星！
And who else?
這位是誰？
A slave for us. It will be nice to have someone to help mop up
是我們的僕人  在我們招呼完我們的小客人後 能有個人幫忙打掃衛生可真不錯
Oh, good work, sister.
Oh  幹得好  姐姐
And just in time, I see! You look awful!
時間剛剛好  我來瞧瞧  你看起來真可怕！
Who are you?
你是誰？
What business do you have here?
你在這兒幹什麼？
Septimus?
Septimus？
I knew your brother, Primus.
我認識你哥哥  Primus
Unless you wish to meet him in the afterlife,
除非你想去地獄見他  否則...
I suggest you answer my question. What are you doing here?
建議你還是乖乖的回答我的問題： 你在這裡幹什麼？
I might ask you the same thing.
我也想問你同樣的問題
There are four of them.
他們一共有四個人
Do as I say and we may stand a chance.
照我說的做我們就還有機會
Wait. How do I know you can be trusted?
等等  我怎麼知道你信不信得過
You don't. Why? Do you have a choice?
你不信我？為什麼？你還有其他選擇麼？
- No. - Well, then, let's go.
- No - Well   那麼  我們走
Get off me! Get off!
放開我！放手！
- Una? - Septimus.
- Una？ - Septimus
- Una! - Sister!
- Una！ - 妹妹！
Tristan! No! Tristan!
Tristan! No! Tristan!
I'm your... I'm your... I'm your mother.
我是你的...我是你的...我是你的母親
I'm your mother.
我是你的母親
- Rather well. - Good riddance to you. Yes.
- 幹得相當好 - 總算幹掉你了  Yes
Oh!
Oh!
Let's put out those flames.
讓我們把火滅了
Shall we?
如何？
So, what happens now?
那麼  現在怎麼辦呢？
We have to learn to live with each other.
我們得學著一起生活了
Forever?
永遠嗎？
Let's get on with it.
我們來繼續吧
Be the man that I know you are.
像個男人一樣  我知道你行的
- Get outside. - Okay.
- 躲在外面 - Okay
Go.
走
- Tristan! - Get him.
- Tristan！ - 抓住他
Get off!
滾開
So, what's it to be, Prince Charming? Frog or tadpole?
那麼  你想變成什麼  白馬王子？青蛙還是蝌蚪？
Septimus?
Septimus？
Tristan!
Tristan！
Youth.
年輕
Beauty.
美貌
It all seems meaningless now.
現在對我都沒有意義了
My sisters are dead!
我的姐妹們都死了
Everything I cared about gone.
我關心的一切都...沒有了
Go.
走吧
Go!
走吧！
No!
No!
I owe you thanks, boy.
我欠你一句感謝  孩子
What use was her heart to me when it was broken?
她的心要是碎了  對我來說還有什麼用？
And you got rid of my sisters and now I can have it all for myself.
你除掉了我的姐妹們 現在它就完全歸我一個人享用了
- Hold me tight and close your eyes. - What? Why?
- 抱緊我  閉上眼睛 - 幹什麼？為什麼？
What do stars do?
星星能做什麼？
Shine.
閃耀
- Bravo! - Yeah!
- 精彩啊! - Yeah!
Very good.
非常好
Why didn't you do that earlier?
為什麼你不早用這招？
I couldn't have done that without you. No star can shine with a broken heart.
沒有你我辦不到 星星要是心碎了就無法發光的了
I thought I'd lost you.
我以為我會失去你
But you came back.
但是你回來了
Of course I did. I love you.
我當然要回來了  我愛你
Come on.
來吧
Tristan.
Tristan
The last surviving male heir of the Stormhold bloodline.
Stormhold城皇族血統最後的男性繼承人
It's you, Tristan.
就是你  Tristan
But if he's the new King of Stormhold, then...
但如果他是Stormhold城的新國王  那...
I crown thee King Tristan of Stormhold.
我為Stormhold城的Tristan國王加冕
Yeah!
Yeah!
My gift to you.
這是我送你們的禮物
To you both.
給你們兩個的
Thank you.
謝謝
They ruled for 80 years.
他們統治了80年
But no man can live forever,
但是沒人可以永生不死
except he who possesses the heart of a star.
除非他擁有星星的心
And Yvaine had given hers to Tristan completely.
Yvaine也把真心完全獻給了Tristan
When their children and grandchildren were grown,
當他們的子子孫孫們都長大後
it was time to light the Babylon candle.
就是點燃巴比倫蠟燭的時候了
And they still live happily ever after.
從此以後  他們永遠幸福快樂的生活著